Curriculum Vitae

Ulf Aslak Jensen

Telephone: +45 30224839 E-mail: ulfaslak@gmail.com

Website: ulfaslak.com Date of birth: 02/02-1990

Summary

Master student and teaching assistant at the Technical University of Denmark, pursuing a degree in Digital Media Engineering with specialisation in Data Science. Works part time as a Data Science student assistant at Trustpilot, developing software for automation of fraud detection. Career minded person that has worked with companies professionally or academically - and often both - since early in his studies.

Personal description

I am born in Denmark, half Icelandic, the youngest of three. I come from an upbringing of frequent traveling and have brought this habit into my adult life. I lead an active lifestyle with lots of cycling, yoga and skateboarding. I'm good at social situations, good at presenting, teaching and explaining my work, and most effective in projects with equal parts teamwork and alone-work. My experiences from working together with companies, as a an intern, a student assistant and a consultant has given me a lot of career-related experience and has helped me clarify my abilities and goals, and build my network. Spending up to 20 hours a week on extracurricular activities, alongside my studies at DTU, has taught me time-management skills crucial to my academic achievements. I have a technical mindset and have always enjoyed applying myself.

Work Experience

aug. 2015-	Data Science Student Assistant Trustpilot A/S, Copenhagen Data analysis and software development using Python, R and C#. Working with machine learning algorithms to detect fake reviews on Trustpilot. This job started as an internship.
2014–2015	Consultant Animation Artist Sterlitech Corporation, Seattle/Web Producing 3D animation videos using Blender, Python and HPC technology, as substitutes for live product demos.
jan. 2013–	Teaching Assistant DTU (Technical University of Denmark), Lyngby Teaching assistant in 'Physics 1' (jan. 2013–jun. 2015) and 'Computational Tools for Big Data' (aug. 2015–). In-class problem solving assistance and correction of homework.
2011–2013	Review Analyst Popular AB, Stockholm/Web Picking out good quotes from movie and album reviews. Developing visual assistance tools using JavaScript and Python.

Education

2014–	M.Sc Engineering, Digital Media Engineering. DTU (Technical University of Denmark) Average: 11.0 (GPA: 3.8)
2012	Student exchange, Physics and Nanotechnology . NUS (National University of Singapore)
2010–2014	B.Sc Engineering, Physics and Nanotechnology . DTU (Technical University of Denmark). Average: 8.1 (GPA: 3.0) Thesis: 12 (A)
2007–2009	Upper secondary programme, Mathematics/Physics. Gribskov Gymnasium Average: 10.0 (GPA: 3.3)
1995–2005	Grade school, Tingbakkeskolen, Esrum/Esbønderup Average: 11.0 (GPA: 3.8)

Volunteer work

apr. 2015	Member of the Board of Appeals DTU (Technical University of Denmark), Lyngby Partaking in re-evaluation of exam projects in the course '42490, TEMO'.
dec. 2013/14	Pre-exam tutoring DTU (Technical University of Denmark), Lyngby Helping students understand key concepts in the course 'Physics 1'.
2010-2012	Handicap Dancing Instructor Aftenskolen v/ Lis Cronberg, Hillerød Weekly dancing lessons with mentally and/or physically handicapped people of all ages.
2010–	Writer/Editor Wunderbaum Magazine, Copenhagen/Web Sporadically committing articles and edits to this biannually published magazine.
2008-2010	Music Booker Toldkammeret, Helsingør Responsible for booking bands and arranging events for an indie music club. We hosted artists such as Fallulah, Analogik, Vinnie Who and When Saints Go Machine.

Recommendations

aug. 2015	"Ulf was a very active student contributing in lectures as well as in practicals and in the laboratory. In addition to his professional contributions I got a very good impression of Ulf as an engaged and well-liked student. ()"
	- Carsten Knudsen, Senior Executive Education Officer, DTU Physics
jan. 2014	"He is a quick learner and very open to venture into new scientific disciplines. His interdisciplinary interest profile is highly beneficial for complex projects involving both academic and industrial partners. In addition he has an easy-going personality with a good flair for team-work which is essential in our type of project. ()"
	- Claus Helix Nielsen, Vice President, Aquaporin A/S
feb. 2012	"Aslak is a bright, inquisitive student, cheerful, always well prepared, and always extremely thorough with homework. He very quickly acquired a remarkable grasp of the central points and techniques in the not always trivial material, and proceeded to get top marks at the written exam. ()"
	- Poul Hjorth, Associate Professor, DTU Mathematics

Miscellaneous

Publication

sep. 2015 "Open-Source CFD Model for Optimization of Forward Osmosis and Reverse Osmosis Membrane Modules" (being reviewed), Journal of Membrane Science

Conference

nov. 2014 Talk on CFD optimisation of membrane modules, **DRWIP2014** (Danish Water Research and Innovation Platform 2014), Copenhagen

Competitions

feb. 2015	Finalist, EBEC15 (European BEST Engineering Competition 2015), Lyngby
jun. 2014	4th place, DTU Grøn Dyst , Lyngby
jun. 2012	Participant, DTU Grøn Dyst , Lyngby

Projects

aug. 2015	"Membrane Testing System Tutorial", Animation Video Instructive animation video made in Blender, illustrating how to use the Sterlitech Sepa CF Membrane Testing System. Displayed at https://youtu.be/C6vvIFSd464.
jun. 2015	"Analysing bias patterns in the movie reviewing community", Visualisation Visualisations showing rating bias patterns among movie critics across the world, based on review data scraped from rottentomatoes.com. The project is exhibited on http://cwii.frwaw.itu.dk/movie_critics/ .
dec. 2014	"Predicting the Danish Parliament", Machine Learning A web service that allows users to enter information about a law proposition, and get instant predictions on how different members of parliament are going to vote. Available at http://ec2-54-68-181-171.us-west-2.compute.amazonaws.com:8000/query_folketinget/.
dec. 2014	"Why do people follow bots?", Machine Learning An exploratory study in which we created a Twitter bot and attracted over 2000 followers, such as to study the mechanisms that drove them to follow us. Available at http://ulfaslak.com/images/sigproc-sp.pdf.

Skills

Computer related

Coding: Python, R, MATLAB, JavaScript, C#, Swift (iOS)

Database systems: SQL, NoSQL, Neo4j

Tools and tech.: D3, Hadoop MapReduce, Apache Spark, Amazon ML, Blender

Other: HTML, CSS, LaTeX, RegEx, Git, OpenFOAM, Unix Terminal

General

Languages: Danish (native), English (excellent), German (intermediate), Icelandic (basic)

Training: Drivers license (B), First aid training, Cleanroom fabrication, voice training (acting)